Emad Hussien

Backend Engineer (Java, Node) More than a year of hands-on software development experience focusing on backend technologies and full-stack applications. Built and delivered various projects, including side projects, freelance work, and internships. I enjoy turning ideas into reality.

emadhussien.fcis@gmail.com +201556966214 Cairo, Egypt <u>LinkedIn Link</u> <u>GitHub Link</u>

WORK EXPERIENCE

Klivvr

Egypt, Cairo

AUG 2024 - PRESENT

Full Stack Intern

Klivvr is a fintech Egyptian company subsidiary of Orascom Financial Holding (OFH).

- Implemented MongoDB aggregation, filtering, and pagination to reduce the need to load large datasets at once.
- Reduced backend traffic and API complexity by developing a flexible PATCH API that consolidates multiple task updates into a single request.
- Integrated Firebase Storage, Multer, and validation middleware for file uploads.
- implemented real-time task updates and online user tracking using Socket.IO technologies: NodeJs, Typescript, Express, MongoDB, React, Tailwind, Socket IO.

3 7 7 7 7 7 9

Freelance (E-Commerce Web App)

Frontend Engineer

Egypt, Cairo

JAN 2024 - MAR 2024

- Improved system stability and performance, by Resolving legacy code issues.
- enhanced security and simplified the login process by Integrating with Firebase SDK for Google login,
- Integrated Paymob for efficient payment processing.

technologies: Javascript, React, Redux, Tailwind, Material UI.

EDUCATION

Ain Shams University, (Bachelor of Computer and Information Sciences).

Egypt, Cairo

June 2023

PROJECTS

Food Delivery System (JUL 2024 - PRESENT). Backend Engineer.

- Built a scalable system for restaurant management, customer orders, and reviews, enhancing API performance with pagination.
- Integrated Stripe for secure payments and Keycloak for authentication to secure API endpoints.
- Implemented validation, global exception handling, and unit testing to ensure system reliability.

technologies: Spring Boot, MySQL, JPA, REST APIs, Mockito, Stripe, Keycloak.

E-commerce application (AUG 2023 - JAN 2023). Backend Engineer.

- Developed CRUD operations with MVC architecture.
- Implemented authentication and authorization with JWT, including refresh tokens for enhanced security.

technologies: Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Stripe API, JWT, MVC

TECHNOLOGIES

Stack

Java, Spring Boot, H2 Database, JPA, REST API, MySQL, Mockito, Keycloak.

Other

NodeJS, ExpressJS, TypeScript, ReactJS. MongoDB, Firebase, Redux, Github, Tailwind, Material Ui

CERTIFICATES

CS50: Introduction to Computer Science (2020)

Solved the 9 problem sets and developed a web application final project.

Responsive Web Design (2022)

Built 5 frontend projects.

LANGUAGES

Arabic native English C1, fluent